OK, hi.
嗨
Last lecture in midterm scope.
期中范围内的最后一堂课
It's also the last lecture where I have to do a crap ton of Java coding, so I get to relax after this.
这也是我必须做大量Java编码的最后一堂课 所以之后我可以放松一下
All of today is focused on building one thing, which is the ArraySet.
今天的全部内容都集中在构建一个东西上 那就是ArraySet
So what's a set?
那么什么是集合
Maybe you remember it from 61A.
也许你还记得它是从61A中学到的
Maybe you remember I briefly mentioned it last time.
也许你还记得我上次简要提到过
So a set is an unordered collection of objects.
集合就是一组无序的对象
So it's not like a list where I can say, give me the fifth element.
不像列表那样我能说 给我第五个元素
In a set, there is no order.
在一个集合中 没有顺序
You just throw these into the collection.
你只是把它们扔进集合里
And a set can have no duplicates.
而且集合中不允许重复
So if I add all these cities, and I add the city Oakland twice, then the second add has no effect.
如果我添加所有这些城市 再添加一次奥克兰这个城市 那么第二次添加没有任何效果
This set only has four things.
这个集合只有四个元素
And what can you do with the set?
你能用集合做什么呢
You can add things to the set, and you can ask if the set contains an item.
你可以向集合添加东西 并且你可以询问集合是否包含某项
And that's it.
就是这样
So it's unordered.
它是无序的
I cannot say what's the fifth thing in the set.
我不能说集合中的第五个是什么东西
There's no order.
没有顺序
There are no duplicates.
没有重复项
But I can add things to the set and ask if the set contains certain things.
但是我可以向集合添加东西 并询问集合是否包含某些东西
OK, so how do you build a set?
那么如何构建一个集合呢
Well, today we're going to build a set using a backing array.
今天我们将使用支持数组构建一个集合
So we're going to use an array to store the items.
我们将使用一个数组来存储这些项
And then we're going to build a class around the array to implement set behavior.
然后我们将围绕数组构建一个类来实现集合行为
So that's where we'll start.
这就是我们要开始的地方
And then we'll start throwing in some new fancy features to make the set more like something that you see in Java.
然后我们将添加一些新的高级功能 使集合更像在Java中看到的东西
To start building the set, we have to build some basic operations, like how do you add things to the set?
开始构建集合 我们必须构建一些基本操作 比如如何向集合中添加东西
How do you check if the set contains things?
如何检查集合中是否包含东西
How do you check the size of the set?
如何检查集合的大小
So I could start typing these out.
我可以开始打这些了
But in the interest of not boring you, I will just show you what I have so far.
但出于不想让你感到无聊的考虑 我只会展示给你目前为止的内容
So most of these you could probably come up with yourself.
大多数情况下 这些你可能自己能想到
And in fact, if you want extra practice, you can go try it.
实际上 如果你想要额外练习 你可以去尝试一下
But what I have here is kind of similar to the ArrayList.
但我这里有的东西和 ArrayList 有点相似
I have an underlying array of items.
我有一个基础数组的项目
And here I'm using a generic type T, because it could be a set of strings, a set of integers, a set of dogs, who knows what.
这里我使用了一个泛型类型 T 因为它可以是一组字符串、一组整数、一组狗 谁知道呢
I'll have a size variable, just like I always have.
我会有一个大小变量 就像我以前一直有的那样
And then when I instantiate the array set, I'll create a new array of 100 items.
然后当我实例化数组集时 我会创建一个新的包含 100 个项目的数组
And you might wonder, well, what if I run out of space?
也许你会想 那如果我空间用完了怎么办
You can resize, just like we did in the array list.
你可以调整大小 就像我们在数组列表中所做的那样
I'm not going to implement resizing, just because it's extra code and there's already a lot of code to stare at.
我不打算实现调整大小 因为这是额外的代码 而且已经有很多代码可以看了
But if you want to, you could certainly add resizing.
但如果你想的话 你当然可以添加调整大小的功能
I'm just omitting it because I don't have a lot of space in the slide.
我只是省略了它 因为幻灯片上的空间不多
OK.
So what else can you do? You can add things.
那么你还能做什么  你可以添加东西
And notice that when you're adding things, I have to first say, if it's already in the set, don't do anything.
请注意 当你添加东西时 我必须首先说 如果它已经在集合中 就不要做任何事情
Return.
返回
Otherwise, add it to the array.
否则 将其添加到数组中
OK, great.
很棒
And you can imagine throwing some extra resizing if you feel like it.
而且你可以想象如果你觉得需要的话添加一些额外的调整大小
And you want to make this infinitely extensible.
而且你想要使其无限可扩展
But for now, I'm not going to.
但是目前 我不打算这样做
How do you check if it contains an item?
你如何检查它是否包含一个项
You go through the array.
你遍历数组
If any of the items equals x, you return true.
如果任何项等于x 就返回true
If you don't find it, it's false.
如果找不到 就是false
OK, so pretty normal set stuff.
这是相当正常的集合操作
We can check that it works, hopefully.
我们可以检查它是否有效 希望如此
So I could add 5, 23, and 42.
我可以添加5、23和42
And I could ask the array set, do you contain 42?
然后我可以问数组集 你包含42吗
Do you contain 50?
你包含50吗
And it says, true, I do contain 42.
它说 是的 我确实包含42
But I do not contain 50.
但我不包含50
OK, so it seems like things are working pretty well.
看起来事情运行得相当顺利
Everyone happy with my basic array set so far?
大家对我的基本数组设置都满意吗
I kind of fast-forwarded it a little bit through the basic operations, just so we can get to all the fancy stuff.
我有点快进了一下基本操作 这样我们就能进入所有的花哨东西了
OK, here comes the fancy stuff.
现在开始花哨的东西
I guess here's the constructor.
我猜这是构造函数
We talked about this.
我们谈过这个了
There's the contains method.
这里是包含方法
Check for duplicates, or check if it contains the item.
检查重复项 或检查是否包含该项
And then when you add, you check for duplicates.
然后当你添加时 你会检查重复项
OK, great.
太棒了
So here comes the fun stuff.
接下来就是有趣的事情了
I have three fun things to show you today.
今天我有三个有趣的东西要给你看
There's three extra features we're going to add to our array set.
我们将向我们的数组集合添加三个额外的功能
And the first one is going to be some sort of iteration feature.
第一个将是某种迭代功能
So what do I mean by that?
那我是什么意思呢
Well, maybe, as you've been working on, I don't know, project 0, project 1, you've seen this funny syntax.
也许在你一直在做项目0、项目1之类的项目时 你见过这种有趣的语法
For int i in the set, print out the item.
对于集合中的每个元素 使用增强型for循环打印出该元素
Java calls this the enhanced for loop.
Java将其称为增强型for循环
So instead of saying i equals 0, i less than whatever, you could say something like for int i in javaset and then iterate through all the items in javaset.
不是说 i 等于 0 i 小于某个值 而是可以这样说 for int i in javaset 然后遍历 javaset 中的所有项
But how does this actually work?
但这到底是怎么运作的呢
So to figure it out, we're going to somehow peel away the magic behind this enhanced for loop.
为了弄清楚 我们要揭开这个增强的 for 循环背后的魔法
And I want to have our javaset support the enhanced for loop.
我想让我们的 javaset 支持增强的 for 循环
OK.
So we could try this.
那我们可以试试这个
I could go in and create.
我可以进去创建
This is from the Java standard library, the Java built-in set.
这是来自Java标准库的 Java内置的集合
And if I say for int i in the set, print out i, I would get 5, 23, and 42.
如果我说for int i在集合中 打印出i 我会得到5、23和42
So let's take this idea that works perfectly fine on the Java library.
让我们拿这个在Java库中完美运行的想法来试试
Let's try it on ours.
让我们在我们的库中尝试一下
So here I have the same code as before.
这里我有和之前一样的代码
For int i in my set, as is the set that I wrote,
对于我的集合中的int i 就像我写的那个集合一样
I want to print it out.
我想把它打印出来
OK, so I try it.
我试试
OK, and it complains.
它抱怨了
It says, I wanted this other thing, but you gave me an array set.
它说 我想要另一件东西 但你给了我一个数组集
I don't know what this means.
我不知道这意味着什么
OK, so as of now, we cannot do for int i and s. So why?
截止目前 我们不能为 int i 和 s 进行 那么为什么呢
What do we have to add to make this supported?
我们需要添加什么来支持这个
So it complains.
它就是在抱怨
It says, I wanted this thing, but you gave me some array set.
它说 我想要这个东西 但你给了我一些数组集合
OK, so whatever that means, let's strip away the magic.
好吧 不管那意味着什么 让我们去掉魔法
Let's find out what's going on.
让我们弄清楚发生了什么
OK, so the secret is that this code that looks so nice that says for int i and aset, it really is the equivalent of some uglier code.
所以秘密就是这段看起来很好的代码 说的是对于整数i和aset 它实际上等同于一些更丑陋的代码
So instead of writing this, I could write this uglier code on the right, and it's exactly the same.
我可以写这个 而不是写右边的更丑陋的代码 但它完全相同
So anytime you see code on the left, it's really, secretly doing the code on the right, but written in a nicer way.
每当你看到左边的代码时 实际上它在偷偷地执行右边的代码 但用更好的方式写出来
So what is the code on the right doing?
那么右边的代码在做什么呢
So to translate a little bit, what's going on here is I'm going to create some sort of object called a seer for reasons that will become clear in a little bit.
简单来说 这里发生的是我要创建一个叫做预言者的对象 为了一会儿会变得清楚的原因
So I'm going to somehow call a method called iterator.
我要以某种方式调用一个叫做迭代器的方法
It's going to give me something called an iterator, which I'll name seer.
它会给我一些叫做迭代器的东西 我会把它命名为预言者
And then somehow I'm going to ask the seer, seer, as long as there's more things that you can see, please give me the next thing and then print it out.
然后我要询问预言者 只要你能看到更多的东西 请给我下一样东西然后打印出来
And the printing is the operation that I want to do.
打印是我想要做的操作
Someone wants me to speak closer.
有人要我说得更近一点
OK.
OK, I'll speak really loud.
我会说得很大声
Let's do it.
咱们开始吧
OK, cool.
很酷
So seer, as long as there's more things that you can see, please print out the next thing or get the next thing for me so I can print it out.
只要还有更多你能看到的东西 请打印出下一个东西 或者为我获取下一个东西 这样我就可以打印出来
So this ugly code on the right is equivalent to the code on the left.
右边这段丑陋的代码等同于左边的代码
So somehow, I want to make my array set support this ugly code on the right so that I can support the code on the left.
我想要以某种方式使我的数组集支持右边这段丑陋的代码 这样我就可以支持左边的代码
OK.
So what is the code on the right doing?
右边的代码在做什么
Well, I guess to strip it away even further, what we want is we want some sort of object called an iterator.
进一步简化来说 我们需要的是一个叫做迭代器的对象
And I kind of like to think of the iterator as like, it's like a little wizard.
我喜欢把迭代器想象成一个小巫师
So what it is, is it's some object.
它是一个对象
Again, if you think of object-oriented programming as all these characters,
再说一次 如果你认为面向对象编程就是所有这些角色
living in my code that model objects in the real world.
它们生活在我的代码中 模拟现实世界中的对象
The iterator, it's like a little wizard, and it's going to look inside my ArraySet, and it's going to step through the ArraySet, returning items one by one.
迭代器就像一个小巫师 它会检查我的ArraySet 一步步地遍历ArraySet 逐一返回项
So when I say javaset.iterator, what I want is I want the creation of a brand new wizard, and the wizard is going to be looking into the set that I have, which was the 5, 23, and 42.
当我说javaset.iterator时 我的意思是我想要创建一个全新的巫师 这个巫师将查看我拥有的set 其中包括5、23和42
So I call javaset.iterator, and I get this wonderful little wizard.
我调用javaset.iterator 然后我得到这个很棒的小巫师
It's got the little crystal ball, and it's looking inside my set.
它有一个小水晶球 正在查看我的set
And then what can I do with the iterator now that I have this iterator object?
那么 既然我有了这个迭代器对象 我可以做些什么呢
Well, you can ask this wizard two questions.
你可以向这个巫师提出两个问题
So one of the questions you can ask is, wizard, is there something else that you can give to me?
你可以问巫师 有没有其他东西可以给我
And here the wizard looks, and it says, yeah, I'm looking at the number 5.
这里巫师看了看 它说 是的 我正在看数字 5
So it says, true.
所以它说 真的
has next.
有下一个
There's something else I can give you.
还有其他我可以给你的东西
And then the second thing you can ask of the wizard is you can say, give me the next thing.
然后你可以问巫师的第二件事情是 你可以说 给我下一件事情
And when you call next, there's actually two things that happen.
当你调用下一个时 实际上会发生两件事情
So one of the things that happens is the wizard is going to shout whatever it's looking at right now.
其中一件事情是 巫师会大声喊出它现在正在看的东西
It's also going to take a step to the next thing in the array, in the set, in whatever data structure you're iterating through.
它还会向数组中的下一个步骤前进 向集合中的下一个步骤前进 向你正在迭代的任何数据结构中的下一个步骤前进
So let's watch that in action.
让我们看看它是如何运作的
So I say seer.next, and it does two things.
我说 seer.next 它会做两件事
It's going to yell five, and then it steps over to the next item.
它会喊5 然后它会跨到下一个项目
OK, great.
很棒
And we're in a while loop, so we'll go again.
我们正在一个 while 循环中 所以我们会再次执行
We say, seer, do you have more things that you can see?
我们说 seer 你还有更多的东西可以看到吗
And the seer says, true.
先知说 没错
I'm looking at something right here.
我正在看这个东西
So I will call seer.next.
我会调用 seer.next
What will it do?
那会发生什么
It will shout to the world the current item and then take another step.
它会向世界大喊当前项目 然后再迈出一步
So it shouts 23 and then takes a step.
它喊了 23 然后迈出一步
OK, finally we ask the seer, do you have more things you can see?
最后我们问先知 你还能看到更多东西吗
Yeah, I'm looking at one right here.
是的 我正在看这个
So I'll call next, and the seer will yell 42, and then it will step to the next thing, which is off the end of the array.
我会接下来调用 先知会喊42 然后它会移到数组末尾之外的下一个事物
And now if I ask the seer, do you have more things that you can see?
现在如果我问先知 你还能看到其他的事物吗
The seer says, false.
先知说 false
I don't have anything else.
我没有其他东西
So that's the idea.
这就是思路
Secretly, when I write the enhanced for loop, what I'm really doing is I'm creating this new wizard object.
暗地里 当我编写增强型for循环时 我真正在做的是创建这个新的巫师对象
And I am in a loop asking the seer, do you have something else to give?
我正在一个循环中询问先知 你还有别的东西要给吗
If so, give it to me using the next method.
如果有的话 用下一个方法给我
And remember, the next method, what does it do?
还记得 下一个方法 它是做什么的吗
It returns the current item and then steps one over.
它返回当前项目 然后向前一步
So this is the process I want.
这就是我想要的过程
I want this code to work in order for my enhanced for loop to work.
我希望这段代码能按顺序运行 这样我的增强for循环才能正常工作
OK, thoughts, questions, opinions about the wizarding process that you just saw?
对于刚刚看到的巫术过程 你有什么想法、问题或意见吗
OK.
Cool.
很酷
So I guess the question for you then is, how do we actually implement this?
那么我猜问题对你来说就是 我们到底如何实现这个
So I'm going to have to go into my ArraySet and add extra code to make this C-er process work.
我得进入我的 ArraySet 并添加额外的代码 让这个 C-er 进程工作
So what extra code do I have to add?
那么我需要添加什么额外的代码
There's a couple of choices for you to ponder.
你可以考虑一下几个选择
And maybe to help you, you can consider, remember, the code on the right is equivalent to the code on the left.
也许可以帮助你的是 你可以考虑一下 右边的代码等价于左边的代码
So we're going to try to get this code on the right working.
我们要尝试让这段代码正常运行
So if I paste this code on the right, I can think, you can ponder.
如果我把这段代码直接粘贴到右边 我可以思考 你也可以思考
If I paste this code on the right directly into my ArraySet, is it going to work?
如果我把这段代码直接粘贴到我的ArraySet中 它会工作吗
Well, it's going to complain in a couple of places, right?
嗯 它会在一些地方抱怨 对吧
For example, my set, it currently does not have an iterator method.
例如 我的集合 它目前没有一个迭代器方法
So I'm probably going to have to add something like an iterator method that returns the new wizard.
我可能需要添加类似于迭代器方法的东西 它返回新的向导
And then that wizard object itself, that CR object, it must have a hasNext method and a next method.
然后这个向导对象本身 那个CR对象 它必须有一个hasNext方法和一个next方法
So somehow, I'm going to have to add extra code.
在某种程度上 我将不得不添加额外的代码
I'm going to have to add an iterator method inside the array set to give me the new wizard.
我将不得不在数组集合内部添加一个迭代器方法 以便为我生成新的向导
And then the wizard itself has to have hasNext and next.
然后向导本身必须具有hasNext和next方法
OK.
So with all of that in mind, we're going to go try it.
考虑到所有这些 我们将去尝试它
We're going to have to add an iterator method, wherever that is.
我们将不得不添加一个迭代器方法 无论它在哪里
And then the iterator object is going to have to have a hasNext and a next.
然后迭代器对象将不得不具有hasNext和next方法
OK.
All this sounds kind of mysterious, so let's go give it a shot.
这些听起来有点神秘 所以让我们去试试吧
So here I am.
我在这里
This is the code that you saw from earlier, the ugly wizarding process.
这就是你之前看到的代码 那个丑陋的巫术过程
And it starts complaining.
然后它开始抱怨
It says,
它说
Your object S does not have an iterator method.
你的对象 S 没有迭代器方法
It's not there.
这里没有
I look.
我看看
This contains.
这包含
There's add.
有添加
No iterator.
没有迭代器
So I guess we'll have to add one.
我猜我们得添加一个
So we'll say public.
我们会说公共
And what do I want to return?
我想要返回什么呢
According to the ugly code, I want to return this funny thing called iterator.
根据丑陋的代码 我想要返回这个有趣的东西叫做迭代器
So it's some sort of interface.
这是某种接口
OK.
OK, great.
太棒了
It is complaining because I guess I have to import the iterator library.
它在抱怨 因为我猜我得导入迭代器库
There it is.
就是这样
Good.
Thank you, IntelliJ.
谢谢 IntelliJ
OK, so what do I return?
那我应该返回什么
I have to return some sort of iterator object.
我得返回某种迭代器对象
It's the seer, so maybe I'll return new ArraySetIterator something.
这是个集合 也许我会返回一个新的 ArraySetIterator 之类的东西
But this is an object that I haven't created yet.
但是这是一个我还没有创建的对象
So I have to go make one of those wizard things.
我得去制造一个那种巫师的东西
So I could make it in a separate file, like the comparator from last time.
我可以把它放在一个单独的文件中 就像上次的比较器
But instead, I'm going to think and realize, you know what?
但是 相反 我要思考并意识到 你知道吗
This wizard, it's not like its own standalone thing.
这个向导 不是像它自己独立的东西
It's like something that belongs to an ArraySet.
它更像是属于一个ArraySet的东西
Every wizard has its own little ArraySet that it makes friends with, that it looks inside.
每个向导都有自己的小ArraySet 它与之交友 它查看其中的内容
So instead of making the wizard its own separate class, I'm actually going to make it inside the ArraySet class.
我不打算把向导作为独立的类 而是实际上将其放在ArraySet类内部
And the only reason why I'm doing this is because I think this is not its own feature, but I think it's something specific to an ArraySet.
我这样做的唯一原因是因为我认为这不是它自己的特性 而是与ArraySet相关的某种特定的东西
And in fact, each wizard has its own little ArraySet that it can step through.
其实 每个巫师都有自己的小ArraySet 可以逐个步进
So I like it here. And I can even add a comment.
我喜欢这里  而且我甚至可以添加一条评论
I could say, returns an iterator, a.k.a.
我可以说 返回一个迭代器 又名
seer, into me, the current object.
预见者 进入我 当前对象
OK, great.
太棒了
So EraseItIterator, it's starting to complain, and it says, wait a minute.
所以ArrayAetIterator 开始抱怨 它说 等一下
I wanted an iterator type, but you gave me an EraseItIterator.
我想要一个迭代器类型 但你给我一个ArrayAetIterator
So what's it complaining about?
那它抱怨什么
Well, we kind of are realizing that EraseItIterator is an iterator, but Java doesn't know that.
我们有点意识到ArrayAetIterator是一个迭代器 但Java不知道
So we have to tell Java,
我们要告诉Java
This ArraySetIterator is not just any class.
这个ArraySetIterator不只是任何类
It's not like a dog or a planet.
它不像一只狗或一个行星
It's actually a specific type of object.
它实际上是一种特定类型的对象
It's a wizard.
这是一个巫师
It's one of those wizards that we talked about.
这是我们谈论过的那些巫师之一
So I'll say it implements the iterator.
我会说它实现了迭代器
Oh, sorry.
哦 抱歉
I think I messed up one thing.
我觉得我弄错了一件事
So this is a generic type because we're trying to make our ArraySet work for any items.
这是一个泛型类型 因为我们试图让我们的ArraySet适用于任何项目
My apologies.
抱歉
Does that work?
这个可以吗
Is it like this?
是这样吗
Justin, help.
贾斯汀 帮帮忙
Dang, I made 11 lectures without screwing this up.
天啊 我讲了11节课都没有搞砸
OK.
I also practiced this yesterday.
我昨天也练过这个
Is it?
是吗
Oh, I think it's like this.
哦 我觉得是这样的
I want to make it generic, so I think I just stick in... Okay.
我想要让它通用化 我觉得我只需插入...
Great.
太棒了
I think that's perfect.
我觉得那很完美
Okay, sorry about that.
对不起
So, the only reason why I got a little bit tripped up is because the ArraySetIterator, it doesn't just support integers, it has to support any type.
我有点困惑的唯一原因是因为ArraySetIterator 它不仅支持整数 还必须支持任何类型
It could be a seer into an ArraySet of strings, it could be a seer into an ArraySet of integers.
它可以是字符串ArraySet的seer 也可以是整数ArraySet的seer
So I had to make it generic, so I made it generic, adding the T placeholder everywhere.
我不得不把它做成通用的 所以我把它做成通用的 在所有地方都添加了 T 占位符
Okay, my apologies.
我道歉
You know, if you watch the video that Josh makes, he also messes this up in the same place.
你知道 如果你看 Josh 制作的视频 他在同一个地方也搞砸了这个
And I was practicing off his.
而我正是在他的基础上练习的
So I guess I learned his mistake as well.
我想我也学到了他的错误
OK, my bad.
好吧 我犯了个错
All right, so we have our ArraySetIterator.
那么我们有我们的 ArraySetIterator
We've told Java that the ArraySetIterator is an iterator.
我们已经告诉 Java ArraySetIterator 是一个迭代器
It's a specific type of an iterator interface that you defined.
这是你定义的迭代器接口的一种特定类型
So what does the iterator interface need?
那么迭代器接口需要什么呢
According to the interface, which lives somewhere in Java, this wizard has to be able to report if there's a next thing, and it also has to be able to give you the next thing and step forward.
根据接口 在 Java 的某个地方 这个向导必须能够报告是否有下一个元素 而且它还必须能够提供下一个元素并向前移动
And in fact, I can even ask IntelliJ, kind of like you did in Project 1, I could try to override the methods myself,
事实上 我甚至可以像在 Project 1 中那样向 IntelliJ 询问
or I can just be lazy and say, IntelliJ, you tell me what I need to override.
我可以尝试自己覆盖这些方法 或者我可以懒一点 直接让 IntelliJ 告诉我需要覆盖什么
OK, IntelliJ has told me you have to override this thing.
IntelliJ 告诉我你必须覆盖这个
You have to override this thing.
你必须覆盖这个
OK, thank you, IntelliJ.
谢谢 IntelliJ
Inside my ArraySetIterator class, I'm no longer in the ArraySet class.
在我的ArraySetIterator类中 我不再在ArraySet类中
This method that I wrote, I was in the ArraySet class.
这个方法我写的 我在ArraySet类中
I was thinking about how all sets should be able to return a new seer.
我在想所有的集合应该能够返回一个新的seer
But now I'm going to be writing code inside the NestedIteratorSeer class.
但现在我要在NestedIteratorSeer类中编写代码了
So now I'm going to start writing logic to say what the wizard does.
现在我要开始编写逻辑来说明巫师的功能
I want to write about the wizarding process.
我想写关于巫术过程的内容
So I think, how do I, like, capture the idea that there's a wizard and it's, like, stepping through the items in the array?
我觉得 我怎么样才能捕捉到这个想法 就是有个巫师 然后它就在数组里步进 对吧
So maybe I have to, like, somehow keep track of where the wizard is.
可能我得以某种方式记录一下巫师所在的位置
So maybe I'll say, you know, whiz-pause.
我可能会说 你知道 巫咔-暂停
That's the wizard's position.
这就是巫师的位置
You could call it something else if you wanted.
如果你愿意 你也可以取个别的名字
And maybe when I create the new ArraySetIterator for the very first time, I should say the whiz-pause is equal to, well, where should it start?
也许当我第一次创建新的ArraySetIterator时 我应该说巫咔-暂停等于 嗯 它应该从哪里开始呢
Well, maybe you should start at 0.
嗯 也许你应该从0开始
That's the start of the array.
这是数组的开始
I think that's reasonable.
我觉得那很合理
OK, so now we just have to go through and say, if the wizard has this current whiz pause, does it have the next item?
现在我们只需要逐个检查 如果向导有这个当前 wizPos 它是否有下一个项目
Well, how do I check if it's got a next item?
那么 我怎么检查它是否有下一个项目呢
I can check if the whiz pause is less than size.
我可以检查 wizPos 是否小于大小
If so, there's more to give.
如果是 那就还有更多要给的
Otherwise, we've stepped off the end of the array.
否则 我们已经走到数组的末尾了
There's nothing else left to give.
再也没有其他可给予的了
What about next?
下一步呢
That one's a little bit trickier, because it's got to do two things.
这个有点棘手 因为它要做两件事
I first have to say, what's the thing I'm returning?
首先我要说的是 我要返回的是什么
Well, I spelled item wrong.
哦 我拼错了项目的名字
What's the thing I'm returning?
我要返回的是什么
What's the thing that the wizard is currently looking at?
巫师目前正在看的是什么
So that would be items.
那就是物品
Wispos, that's telling me this is the current thing that I'm looking at.
wizPos 这告诉我这是我正在查看的当前内容
OK.
Great.
太好了
And then require type T, provided T. Oh, that's right.
然后需要类型T 提供类型T 哦 对了
I guess I have to cast?
我猜我得强制转换
OK.
Interesting.
有趣
OK.
So items, give me the whiz paused item.
所以项目 给我嗖嗖嗖暂停的项目
OK?
好吗
But then the second thing I have to do is I have to take the wizard and step it forward by one.
但然后我要做的第二件事是 我必须把向导向前推进一步
So how do I do that?
那我怎么做
I could say whiz pause plus equals 1.
我可以说 whiz 暂停 加 1
And then I can return the item that I just fetched.
然后我可以返回刚刚获取的项目
OK.
Looks pretty good.
看起来相当不错
So.
那么
How do I create my wizarding process?
我如何创建我的巫术流程
I keep track internally of the wizard's position.
我在内部跟踪巫师的位置
I instantiate it to zero any time I create a brand new wizard.
每次创建全新的巫师时 我将其实例化为零
And every time I'm stepping through the array, I can ask, is there a next item?
每次我遍历数组时 都可以问 下一个项目在哪里
I check if it's less than size.
我检查它是否小于大小
I can ask for the next item, or I get the current item at whiz pause, and I step the position over by one.
我可以要求下一个项目 或者我可以获得当前项目在whiz暂停处 并将位置向前移动一个
So now it's looking at the next thing.
现在它正在查看下一个事物
So all of this code was just to simulate the wizarding cartoon that you saw from earlier.
所有这些代码只是为了模拟你之前看到的巫术卡通
So with all of this in mind, I can now take this ugly iteration code and see if it works.
考虑到所有这些 我现在可以拿这段丑陋的迭代代码来测试一下
So I guess I'll remove the contains.
我想我会删除contains
We already checked that.
我们已经检查过了
So I'm going to run this.
我要运行这个
I'm going to see if I can successfully step through the array, get the 5, 23, 42.
我要看看能否成功地遍历数组 得到5、23、42
OK, looks pretty good.
看起来挺不错的
So now we have our ugly iteration totally working.
现在我们的循环迭代已经完全正常运行
So then the next challenge is, remember how we said this nice iteration, the nice for-loop syntax, is really just the ugly one in disguise.
那么下一个挑战就是 记住我们说过的这种漂亮的迭代 这种漂亮的for循环语法 实际上只是丑陋迭代的伪装
So if this one works totally fine, well, then this one surely works too, right?
如果这个完全正常运行 那么这个肯定也能正常工作 对吧
Right?
对吧
Well, it's still complaining.
嗯 它还在抱怨
It says, for each not applicable, I wanted something else.
它说 对于每个不适用的情况 我想要别的东西
OK.
So the problem that Java is having is we all know that the ugly process works.
所以 Java 遇到的问题是我们都知道这个丑陋的过程是如何工作的
We know there's an iterator method that returns the seer.
我们知道有一个迭代器方法返回先知
And we know that the seer, the wizard, it knows how to step through the array.
而且我们知道这个先知 这个巫师 它知道如何遍历数组
But the problem is that Java doesn't know.
但问题是Java不知道
So there's an iterator method.
有一个迭代器方法
I mean, you and I can see it.
我的意思是 你和我都能看到它
It's right there.
就在那里
But Java does not know that there is an iterator method.
但Java不知道有一个迭代器方法
So it's not convinced.
它并不确信
It's like, well, what if the ArraySet doesn't have an iterator method?
就像 如果ArraySet没有一个迭代器方法呢
It doesn't know.
它不知道
So in order to tell Java that the ArraySet has an iterator method, in other words, it is something that you can iterate through, I actually have to use a new interface up here called iterable.
为了告诉Java ArraySet有一个迭代器方法 换句话说 它是可以遍历的 我实际上必须在这里使用一个新的接口 叫做iterable
full.
完整的
And this can be a little confusing at first.
一开始可能有点困惑
There's iterator, which is the seer itself.
有迭代器 那就是眼前的东西
And there's iterable, which is like an object with a seer inside.
还有一个iterable 就像一个内部有个视察者的对象
So by saying implements iterable, I'm guaranteeing to Java, this class, because it's an iterable, I guarantee that it has an iterator method.
通过说implements iterable 我向Java保证 这个类因为它是可迭代的 我保证它有一个迭代器方法
And because I guarantee that there's an iterator method, then I can write this nice code.
因为我保证有一个迭代器方法 我可以写这段漂亮的代码
And Java is safe.
而且Java是安全的
It knows I can expand this into the ugly code.
它知道我可以将这扩展为丑陋的代码
It's going to work fine, because I know
它会正常工作 因为我知道
that you implement iterable, you must have this iterator method that creates the new seer.
你实现了可迭代 你必须有这个创建新视图的迭代器方法
So after all that work, after creating that nested class, and also having the array set implement iterable, I write this nice syntax, and I finally get 523.42.
在所有这些工作之后 创建了嵌套类 并且还有数组设置实现了可迭代 我写了这段漂亮的语法 最终得到了523.42
OK, looks pretty good.
看起来很不错
So to summarize a little bit, and then you can hit me with questions, the ugly iteration, what we had to do was we had to add the iterator method.
简单总结一下 然后你可以问我问题 这个不太好的迭代 我们必须做的是添加迭代器方法
This creates the brand new wizard, and then inside the nested wizard class, I had to keep track of its position, and write a hasNext method, and write a next method.
这创建了全新的向导 然后在嵌套的向导类内部 我必须跟踪其位置 并编写 hasNext 方法和编写 next 方法
And then the final thing I had to do was, well, Java just does not know that this ArraySet has an iterator.
然后我必须做的最后一件事是 Java只是不知道这个 ArraySet 有一个迭代器
We saw it, but Java wasn't confident that the ArraySet had an iterator.
我们看到了 但是Java并不确信 ArraySet 有一个迭代器
So to tell Java, to guarantee to Java, yes, I promise you that the ArraySet has an iterator method.
告诉Java 向Java保证 是的 我向你保证 ArraySet 有一个迭代器方法
I can have the ArraySet implement iterable.
我可以让 ArraySet 实现可迭代接口
And what does the iterable interface do?
那么可迭代接口是做什么的呢
It has a single method, iterator.
它有一个单一的方法 iterator
It basically says, if you claim to be part of the iterable interface, you claim that you're an iterable,
基本上是这样说 如果你声称自己是可迭代接口的一部分 你声称自己是可迭代的
you had better have a method that creates a new seer that allows you to step into the object and iterate through it.
最好有一个方法来创建一个新的观察者 允许你步入对象并通过它进行迭代
So it can be a little bit confusing.
可能会有点混乱
The way I think of it is the iterator, this is the seer.
我认为的方式是迭代器 这就是观察者
It's like the wizard itself.
就像巫师本身一样
And the wizard itself, it's not like the wizard is an array set.
而且巫师本身 它并不像巫师是一个数组集
It's not like the array set is a wizard.
就像数组集不是一个巫师一样
So it's not in the hierarchy that we're showing on this slide.
这不是我们在这张幻灯片上展示的层次结构
But the iterator is a wizard whose job in existence is to step through items.
但迭代器是一个向导 其存在的目的是遍历项目
And then the ArraySet, it doesn't implement iterator.
然后ArraySet 它不实现迭代器
It's not a wizard.
它不是一个向导
The ArraySet itself is not the wizard.
ArraySet本身不是向导
But the ArraySet implements iterable.
但ArraySet实现了可迭代
And you can think of iterable as all of the classes in the world that have iterators inside.
你可以把可迭代想象成世界上所有具有迭代器的类
So these are all the objects that have wizards living inside of them, the magic objects with wizards inside.
这些都是里面有巫师居住的物体 带有巫师的魔法物品
That's iterables.
那就是可迭代的
That's arrays.
那就是数组
That's iterating through them.
那就是通过它们进行迭代
No questions?
没有问题吗
Yeah.
是的
I can go back a slide.
我可以回到上一页
Sure.
More slides?
还要更多幻灯片吗
OK.
Ah, that's a great question.
这是一个很棒的问题
Where did the items array come from?
那个items数组是从哪里来的
Let's go find it.
让我们去找找
I think I had to find it up here.
我想我必须在这里找到它
Yeah, great question.
是的 好问题
And the reason I can access it, by the way, and if this makes no sense to you, forget about it, but the ArraySetIterator belongs to a specific array.
顺便说一下 我能访问它的原因 如果这对你来说没有意义 就忘了吧 但ArraySetIterator属于特定的数组
If I put static, then it would complain.
如果我加上static 它就会抱怨
It's OK if that made no sense.
如果这听起来没有意义 没关系
Question?
问题
Yeah, that's a great question, which is sets don't have orders.
是的 那是个好问题 即集合没有顺序
So if you iterate through them, are they going to come out in the same order every time?
如果你遍历它们 它们每次都会以相同的顺序出现吗
Well, that depends on the code that you write.
这取决于你写的代码
So in this case, because I wrote code that looks like this, then it should be the case that I end up getting the items in the order that they're stored in the underlying array.
在这种情况下 因为我写的代码看起来像这样 那么我最终应该得到按照底层数组中存储的顺序排列的项目
But the user of the set does not have to know this.
但是集合的用户不必知道这一点
I could write some documentation if I wanted to.
如果我愿意的话 我可以写一些文档
But the code that I write determines what order the items get printed in.
但是我写的代码决定了项目打印的顺序
That's a great question, though.
这确实是一个很棒的问题
But OK, one more?
但是还有一个吗
Yeah, that's also a great question, which is, do iterables and iterators always have to come together?
是的 这也是一个很好的问题 那就是 可迭代对象和迭代器是否总是要一起出现的
That's a good question.
这是一个很好的问题
I feel like there are some cases out there where you can have an iterator without an iterable or vice versa.
我觉得有些情况下 你可以有一个迭代器而没有可迭代对象 或者反之亦然
I think if you implement iterable,
我认为如果你实现了可迭代对象
Where is this?
这是在哪里
If you implement iterable, you're claiming I am an object with a wizard inside me.
如果你实现了可迭代对象 你就宣称我是一个内部有着巫师的对象
The wizard lives inside me.
这位巫师就在我内部
So I think in that case, there has to be some iterator method living inside of you.
我认为在这种情况下 你里面一定有一些迭代器方法
But I'd say if you implement iterator, you don't necessarily have to implement iterable.
但我要说的是 如果你实现了迭代器 你不一定要实现可迭代的
It's a good question, though. I can't think of a good example off the top of my head.
这是个很好的问题 不过我想不出一个很好的例子来
Yeah, so if you remember generator functions in Python, something like that.
是的 如果你记得 Python 中的生成器函数 就像那样
Yeah.
是的
So that might be an example of an iterator that is an iterable.
这可能是一个迭代器的例子 它是可迭代的
But for today, the way we're building it is we're saying the array set is an iterable.
但是对于今天来说 我们构建的方式是 我们说数组集合是一个可迭代的对象
In other words, it is an object with a wizard living inside of it.
换句话说 它是一个内部有向导的对象
And then in order to implement the wizard, I have to write an iterator method that returns the wizard object itself.
然后为了实现这个向导 我必须编写一个返回向导对象本身的迭代器方法
Then I have to write the whole wizard object.
然后我得写整个向导对象
Great question, though.
虽然这个问题很棒
OK, that's the 4-H loop.
那就是4-H循环
It's the first of three exciting things I get to show to you today.
这是我今天要向你展示的三件令人兴奋的事情中的第一件
By the way, in case you're curious, you can go looking at the real Java code.
顺便说一下 如果你好奇的话 你可以查看真实的Java代码
This is the actual implementation of set.
这就是集合的实际实现
And if you go to set, you'll realize that they also use the iterator method.
如果你查看集合 你会发现它们也使用了迭代器方法
So you can go check it out if you're curious.
如果你好奇的话 你可以去查一下
So that was the iteration, our first of three wonderful features.
那就是迭代 我们三个精彩特性中的第一个
We added the iterator method, created a new wizarding object.
我们添加了迭代器方法 创建了一个新的巫师对象
And then the iterator contained has an x and an x. That was the wizard itself stepping through the array.
然后迭代器包含了一个x和一个x 那就是巫师本身在数组中进行迭代
And then we add the words implement iterable to tell the world that this is an object with a wizard living inside, not just any object.
然后我们加上实现iterable这些词 告诉世界这是一个带着巫师的对象 不仅仅是普通对象
There was one more question?
还有一个问题吗
In the back.
在后面
Hi.
嗨
This one?
这个
Honestly, that's a good question.
说实话 这是个好问题
Because when I was doing this in practice, those were totally fine.
因为在实践中做这件事时 那些都完全没问题
And then Java started complaining, and I had to cast it to a T. So go to the items array.
然后Java开始报错 我不得不将其强制转换为T 请转到items数组
Oh, is it because it wasn't?
是因为它不是吗
Well, it was cast here, so I don't know.
嗯 这里进行了强制转换 所以我不知道
In fact, if you look on the slides, and if you watch me do this in practice, I never casted it, so I'm confused.
实际上 如果你看幻灯片 看我在实践中做这件事 我从未进行过强制转换 所以我很困惑
But the question, by the way, for anyone who didn't hear, was, what's the cast doing here?
但是 顺便说一下 对于任何没听到的人 问题是 这里的强制转换是做什么的
It's a good question.
这是一个好问题
It even says it's cast T to T, so I don't know.
它甚至说它将T强制转换为T 所以我不知道
I think it might have to do with one of these generics.
我觉得这可能与其中一个泛型有关
I don't know.
我不知道
Generics are weird, man.
泛型很奇怪 老兄
Maybe like that?
也许就像这样
Ah, OK.
啊 好的
Oh, wait.
等等
Go back.
回去吧
You want me to go back?
你想让我回去吗
Hmm.
嗯
Yeah, sorry, genetics are kind of weird sometimes.
是的 抱歉 遗传有时候有点奇怪
But now it's complaining, so I don't think that's right.
但现在它在抱怨 所以我觉得那不对
Like that?
像这样
No?
不对吗
OK.
Oh, you want me to get rid of the brackets?
哦 你想让我去掉括号
OK.
Hold.
等一下
It's good.
很好
Don't complain.
别抱怨
OK.
OK, if you're curious, come talk to us.
好吧 如果你好奇的话 就来跟我们聊聊吧
It turns out that generics in Java are just kind of weird.
原来Java中的泛型有点奇怪
I guess what was happening is that there were two placeholders called T because I added an extra T. Oh, well.
我猜导致这种情况的原因是因为我多加了一个T占位符 噢 好吧
OK, but in this case, you just need one to substitute right there.
好吧 但是在这种情况下 你只需要一个来替换这里就行了
OK, sorry, that was a little bit confusing.
好吧 抱歉 那有点混乱
The very, very short answer is if I put T here, it thinks there's a second placeholder that has to be substituted when there is, in fact, not.
非常非常简短的答案是 如果我在这里放了T 它会认为有第二个占位符必须被替换 实际上并不需要
Sorry, not the key idea here.
抱歉 这不是重点
If you know how to implement this for integers or something, you're all set.
如果你知道如何为整数或其他内容实现这个 那就万事大吉了
I just made it generic for more industrial strength code.
我只是将其泛化以提高代码的工业强度
Great question, though.
虽然问题很好
All of that came from the one mistake I had.
所有这些都是由我犯的一个错误引起的
Are we good with iterators?
我们对迭代器满意吗
Done forever, except, I guess, in your assignments?
永远完成了 除非 在你的任务中 我想是这样吧
Next up is object methods.
接下来是对象方法
So there are two object methods we're going to write.
我们要写两个对象方法
So you remember from, I don't know, two lectures ago, all classes extend object.
你还记得 我不知道 两节课之前 所有的类都是对象的子类
That is, all classes are subclasses of object, or all classes inherit the object methods.
也就是说 所有的类都是对象的子类 或者说所有的类都继承了对象方法
So what are the methods of objects?
那么对象的方法是什么
If everything is an object, what are the methods of an object?
如果一切都是对象 那么对象的方法是什么
And remember, we showed you there's all this wild stuff that objects can do.
还记得 我们展示过 对象可以做很多疯狂的事情
A lot of them we just do not care about.
我们很多时候根本不在乎它们
But there are two that we get to unpack today.
今天我们要拆解的有两个
So it turns out all objects have a toString method.
原来所有的对象都有一个toString方法
All objects have an equals method.
所有的对象都有一个equals方法
So why would you want these?
那么你为什么想要这些呢
The two-string method is kind of nice because it takes your current object, and it gives it to you in a string representation.
两个字符串方法还挺不错的 因为它获取你当前的对象 然后以字符串的形式呈现给你
So it takes your current object, converts it into a nice-looking string, and then prints it out for you.
它获取你当前的对象 将其转换为一个漂亮的字符串 然后为你打印出来
So in case you're ever wondering, how does this magic system.out.println method work?
如果你曾经想过 这个魔法的System.out.println方法是怎么工作的
How can it be that I just give this object, like a dog or a tile from project 0, to println?
我怎么会只是给这个对象 就像给 println 一个狗或者项目 0 的瓷砖一样呢
How does it know how to print the object and make it look nice?
它是如何知道如何打印对象并使其看起来漂亮的
It turns out that the println method is secretly calling the toString method of whatever object you're passing in.
原来 println 方法正在秘密调用你传递的任何对象的 toString 方法
So in order to make objects look nice, it's going to use the toString method to print it out.
为了让对象看起来漂亮 它将使用 toString 方法将其打印出来
So for example, in my built-in Java set, this is the set that's built into Java that we're not writing, but they've already written.
例如 在我内置的 Java 集合中 这是 Java 内置的我们不编写的集合 但他们已经编写好了
I could say system.out.println the set, and it will give me this beautifully formatted 543.42.
我可以说 system.out.println 这个集合 它会给我这个漂亮格式的 543.42
And the way that it knows how to do that is because this set object has a toString method that's called by println.
它知道如何做到这一点的方式是因为这个集合对象有一个由 println 调用的 toString 方法
OK.
That seems good.
看起来不错
Let's give it a try.
我们试一试
So I'm done with you iteration.
我完成了一次迭代
Now I want to print out my set and I'm hoping to get a beautifully looking 523 42.
现在我想打印出我的集合 希望得到一个美观的523 42
It's gonna be glorious.
这将是辉煌的
It's gonna be amazing.
这将是令人惊叹的
Okay, so I run it.
我运行它
OK, the suspense.
悬念
OK, so I get this.
我懂了
That doesn't look so beautiful.
这看起来不太美
I get this weird garbage.
我得到了这个奇怪的垃圾
It says something, something, ArraySet at more garbage.
它说了一些东西 ArraySet在更多的垃圾
OK, so my ArraySet printing is not looking so hot.
我的ArraySet打印看起来不太好
And the reason why it's not looking so great is because if you don't override the object method's toString, then you are inheriting the toString method of the object class.
问题在于 如果你不重写对象方法的 toString 那么它看起来并不太好
So I look at my ArraySet, look.
我看了一下我的 ArraySet 看看
No two-string, nowhere.
没有两个字符串 没有任何地方
And so what that means is that I am inheriting the two-string method of my object class, because I am an object.
这意味着我正在继承我的对象类的两个字符串方法 因为我是一个对象
So I get the two-string method for my object.
我得到了我的对象的两个字符串方法
And what does the two-string method in object do?
对象中的两个字符串方法是做什么的
You can click on this link and check it out in the actual Java code, but it turns out
你可以点击这个链接 查看实际的 Java 代码 但结果表明
And it's a little bit out of scope for this class.
这个有点超出了课程范围
But the default toString, it just prints out the name of the object.
但是默认的 toString 方法 它只是打印出对象的名称
So it's ArraySet, an at symbol, and then the memory location of where the ArraySet is.
它是 ArraySet 一个 @ 符号 然后是 ArraySet 所在的内存位置
So all this says is you have an ArraySet object.
这只是说你有一个 ArraySet 对象
It lives at wherever this is in memory.
它存在于内存中的某个位置
And that's basically it.
基本就是这样了
OK.
So that's not what I want.
那不是我想要的
That looks so ugly.
那看起来很丑
I want something that looks a lot nicer.
我想要的是看起来好看多了的东西
So to make my two-string method print out something that looks nicer for my erase set, well, how can I do that?
为了让我的双字符串方法输出一些看起来更好看的东西 那么 我该怎么做呢
I can overwrite what the boss says.
我可以覆盖老板说的话
So I decide that inherited method that my object parent gave to me, it sucks.
我决定 我的对象父类给我的那个继承方法 很烂
It's so ugly.
太丑了
I'm going to write a better one.
我要写一个更好的
So I'm going to jump in.
我要加入
OK, and I'm going to write a better toString method.
我要写一个更好的toString方法
So toString, OK, oops, public string toString returns a string.
所以toString 公共字符串toString返回一个字符串
And I'll add the override tag just to remind myself I am actually overriding the object method.
我会添加重写标签 只是为了提醒自己我确实重写了对象方法
There already was a toString method.
已经有一个toString方法
It was the object class's ugly toString method.
那是对象类的丑陋toString方法
But I want a better one.
但我想要一个更好的
I want to make my array set look nice when I print it.
我想要在打印时让我的数组看起来好看
So how do I build the string?
那么我怎么构建字符串呢
Well, I could start by saying, you know,
我可以开始说 你知道的
Maybe I'll start with, what do you like?
也许我会从 你喜欢什么开始
Do you want brackets?
你想要方括号吗
Do you want curly braces?
你想要花括号吗
Do you want parentheses?
你想要括号吗
Do you want something more exotic?
你想要一些更奇特的东西吗
No parentheses?
不要括号吗
All right.
OK, so we'll start with the parentheses.
我们会从括号开始
OK, great.
太棒了
And then I have to go through each item of the underlying set.
然后我必须遍历底层集合的每个项
So I could use a for loop, but I'm going to be really clever.
我可以使用for循环 但我会变得非常聪明
And I'm going to remember, I just went through all this trouble to write the fancy for loop, so I want to use that.
而且我会记得 我刚刚费了很大的劲写了这个花哨的for循环 所以我想要使用它
So I'm going to say, for item in this.
我要说 对于这个中的项目
What's this?
这是什么
Current object.
当前对象
So I'm iterating through myself.
我正在迭代自己
And as I go through myself, I will take x, and I will add the current objects
当我遍历自己时 我会取x 并且我会添加当前对象
String representation, so I call toString on the current object.
将当前对象转换为字符串表示形式 因此我在当前对象上调用toString方法
Why is this OK?
为什么可以这样
How come I can call toString on this unknown type?
为什么我可以在这个未知类型上调用toString
Because all objects have toStrings.
因为所有对象都有toString方法
Maybe I'll add a space just to make things look nice.
也许我会加一个空格 只是为了让事情看起来好看
And then at the end, I will add a closing parentheses.
然后在最后 我会添加一个右括号
OK, then I can return x.
然后我可以返回x
So that's it.
就是这样了
I iterate through the items.
我遍历这些项目
I add their string representations.
我添加它们的字符串表示
And now, instead of getting this ugly ArraySetAdd gibberish, if I run again,
现在 不再获得这些丑陋的ArraySetAdd胡言乱语 如果我再次运行
hopefully I'm going to use this overridden toString method when I call println, and I get 5, 23, 42.
希望当我调用println时会使用这个重写的toString方法 我会得到5、23、42
Looks pretty good.
看起来相当不错
Yeah, there's an extra space.
是的 有一个额外的空格
If you wanted to, you can make it look nicer.
如果你想的话 你可以让它看起来更好
But in the interest of time, I'm not going to.
但出于时间考虑 我就不这么做了
So you have to live with the space.
你得忍受这个空格
OK.
So one final little issue.
最后再说一个小问题
This is a little bit out of scope, but I just want to bring it up in case you're writing real-world code, which is, turns out,
这有点超出范围 但我只是想提一下 以防你在写实际代码时遇到
in Java, if you try to add two strings together, you're actually making a completely new string.
事实上 在Java中 如果你试图将两个字符串加在一起 你实际上正在创建一个全新的字符串
It's a little bit confusing.
这有点令人困惑
The details are not totally in scope.
具体细节不完全在范围内
But the idea is that if you have a string, and the string is like the entire text of Moby Dick,
但是这个想法是 如果你有一个字符串 而且这个字符串就像《白鲸记》的整个文本一样
And I want to add the letter A to that string.
我想在这个字符串上加上字母A
Java will actually create a brand new string, copy every single character from the old one to the new one, and then add the letter A at the end, preserving the old one where it was.
Java 实际上会创建一个全新的字符串 将旧字符串中的每个字符都复制到新字符串中 然后在末尾添加字母A 保留原来的字符串在原处
And you might ask, well, why would Java do something so dumb like that?
你可能会问 Java为什么要做这样一个愚蠢的事情呢
Well, it has something to do with strings being immutable.
这与字符串是不可变的有关
Non-modifiable, if it makes any sense, that's great.
不可修改 如果这样说有意义的话 那太好了
If it doesn't, that's okay.
如果没有 那也没关系
But basically, all you have to know is the reason why Java is complaining is because if you take a string
但基本上 你只需要知道的原因是 Java抱怨的原因是 如果你拿一个字符串
and you want to add to the string, it's kind of slow because you have to repeatedly make copies of your string to keep adding stuff to it.
想要添加到这个字符串 会有点慢 因为你必须反复复制你的字符串来不断添加东西到它
To make this faster, I'm going to use something kind of weird.
为了让这个过程更快 我要用一些有点奇怪的东西
We haven't really talked about it, and we will not talk about it again.
我们还没有真正讨论过它 而且我们也不会再讨论它了
So if this makes no sense, it's OK.
如果这听起来毫无意义 没关系
But it turns out Java has an object called the StringBuilder.
但事实证明 Java有一个叫做StringBuilder的对象
It's a class.
它是一个类
And the StringBuilder lets you build a string without the concatenation issues.
StringBuilder让你可以构建一个字符串 而不会出现串联的问题
So I'll say new StringBuilder.
那我会说新的 StringBuilder
It's like an object.
就像一个对象
And then I can call append on it to basically throw a bunch of strings into the StringBuilder.
然后我可以在其上调用 append 基本上是将一堆字符串放入 StringBuilder
So you can think of it like a string under construction.
你可以把它想象成一个正在建设中的字符串
It's like some sort of, you know,
就像某种 你知道的
Pressure cooker where I can just throw in a bunch of strings.
压力锅 我可以把一堆字符串扔进去
And then eventually, it'll put all the strings together in a less expensive way.
然后最终 它会以一种更经济的方式把所有字符串拼在一起
So I can call x.append.
我可以调用 x.append
I can call x.append.
So the code looks pretty similar.
代码看起来非常相似
And again, if this makes no sense to you and the toString method was like, that was enough.
而且 如果这对你来说毫无意义 并且 toString 方法就像 那已经足够了
You're showing me all this now.
你现在给我展示这一切
That's totally OK.
这完全没问题
It's not super in scope.
这并不是非常庞大的范围
I just wanted to show it in case you were interested in the true faster way to do this.
我只是想展示一下 以防你对真正更快的方法感兴趣
And then at the end, I had a string builder object, but I want a string.
然后在最后 我有一个字符串生成器对象 但我想要一个字符串
So to get the string out of the pressure cooker, you call toString, and it pops out.
为了从压力锅中取出字符串 你调用toString 它就弹出来了
So this will be a lot faster.
这会快很多
You will not notice it on an array of three things, but if I had an array of like a million things, this code is going to be substantially faster than the one I wrote earlier.
在三个元素的数组上 你可能察觉不到 但如果我有一个包含百万个元素的数组 这段代码将比我之前写的那个要快得多
But again, if you like the earlier one, that's OK for this class.
但同样 如果你喜欢之前的那个 对这门课来说也没问题
I'm just showing it to you in case you ever run into it in real life.
我只是给你看看 以防你在现实生活中遇到它
That's the toString method.
那是 toString 方法
That's the nicer toString method.
那是更友好的 toString 方法
I implemented it.
我实现了它
So there it is.
就是这样
I guess the slides use the curly braces instead.
我猜幻灯片使用大括号而不是圆括号
And we mentioned that the code is slow.
而且我们提到过代码很慢
If you want to make it faster, you can use StringBuilder.
如果你想要让它更快 你可以使用 StringBuilder
But if this makes no sense, that's OK too.
但如果这没有意义 也没关系
But the important thing is we overwrote what the boss said.
但重要的是 我们覆盖了老板说的话
We said, I don't like your ugly two-string method.
我们说 我不喜欢你那丑陋的双字符串方法
So I wrote my own custom, beautiful two-string method.
我写了自己定制的 漂亮的双字符串方法
Questions, thoughts, two-string?
问题 想法 双字符串
Yeah.
是的
Yeah, that's a great question, which is, how come I use this instead of items?
这是一个很棒的问题 就是 为什么我要使用这个而不是items呢
I could use items.
我可以使用items
I believe the main problem with it is that items, oops,
我认为它的主要问题在于items 哎呀
Items?
Items
It is an array.
这是一个数组
You can iterate through it.
你可以遍历它
But it's going to have like 100 things in it.
但它会有大约100个东西在里面
And some of them are probably going to be nulls.
而且其中一些可能会是空值
So I think if I did items, I would just get like 90-something nulls.
我认为如果我做了 items 我只会得到大约 90 多个空值
And it would look kind of weird.
而且看起来会有点奇怪
Whereas if I say this, I'm referring to the current object.
而如果我说这个 我是在指当前的对象
And my CR code, sorry for all the scrolling, my CR code that looks into the current object, it knows to only look for the items that exist and not all of those unused boxes in the underlying array.
而且我的 CR 代码 抱歉需要滚动 我的 CR 代码查看当前对象 它知道只查找存在的项 而不是底层数组中所有未使用的框
It's a good question, though.
不过 这是一个很好的问题
I'll try it just to see.
我会尝试一下 只是为了看看
Any other questions while I try it?
在我尝试的时候还有其他问题吗
I think I would just get lots of nulls.
我觉得我会得到很多空值
Yeah, I guess it complains.
是的 我想它在抱怨
It says, there are nulls.
它说有空值
I don't know what to do with them.
我不知道该怎么办
So this is better.
这样更好
Great question, though.
不过 这是个好问题
Anything on Zoom that the people want to know before I do the third?
在我进行第三步之前 有关 Zoom 的任何事情人们想知道的吗
of three array set features?
关于三个数组集功能
No?
没有吗
OK.
So the third feature is I want to write an equals method.
第三个功能是我想写一个 equals 方法
And at first, this might seem a little weird.
一开始 这可能看起来有点奇怪
You're like, wait a minute.
你可能会想 等一下
There already is an equals thing, right?
已经有一个等于的东西了 对吧
It's equal equals.
是双等号
So here, I have to call out that the equals method and the dot equals method are not the same thing.
在这里 我必须指出 equals 方法和 dot equals 方法不是同一回事
Hmm.
嗯
So it turns out, equal equals, it compares the bits.
原来 双等号会比较比特位
Do you remember the golden rule of equals from so many lectures ago?
还记得那么多讲座前的黄金法则吗
The golden rule of equals says, if I want to check if two things are equal, I simply compare the bits.
黄金法则说 如果我想检查两个东西是否相等 我只需比较比特位
That is, I look at this memory box, which contains the address of some set.
也就是说 我看着这个内存盒子 里面装着某个集合的地址
Go there, find your set.
去那里 找到你的集合
And this memory box, which contains another address.
而这个内存盒子 装着另一个地址
Go there, find your set.
去那里 找到你的集合
And equal equals simply checks, do these two memory boxes have the same address?
而等于等于简单地检查 这两个内存盒子的地址是不是相同的
Are they pointing at the same object?
它们是否指向同一个对象
Are they the same reference?
它们是同一个引用吗
And if so, I return true.
如果是这样 我就返回true
If not, I return false.
如果不是 我就返回false
That's all that equal equals does.
这就是等于等于所做的全部事情
So if I write something like this, I say, I have a new set.
如果我写这样的东西 我说 我有一个新的集合
It's a set with the numbers 5, 23, and 42.
这是一个包含数字5、23和42的集合
Great.
太好了
This creates a new set in memory, 5, 23, 42.
这在内存中创建一个新的集合 5、23、42
It yells the address of it, puts it into javaset.
它喊出它的地址 将其放入javaset
Then I create another memory box, javaset2.
然后我创建另一个内存盒 javaset2
And I assign this to another set living somewhere else in memory with 5, 23, and 42.
然后我将这个分配给另一个存储在内存中的集合 其中包含5、23和42
So now I have two sets.
现在我有两个集合
And they're pointing at different or two memory boxes.
它们指向不同的内存盒或两个内存盒
They're pointing at two different sets in memory.
它们指向内存中的两个不同的集合
So if I use equal equals, I actually get false.
如果我使用等于等于 实际上得到的是false
And what Java is saying is that these two memory boxes, they don't hold the same address.
Java 说的意思是 这两个内存盒子 它们并不存储相同的地址
Their arrows are pointing at different things.
它们的箭头指向不同的东西
They're not the same reference.
它们不是同一个引用
They're pointing at different objects.
它们指向不同的对象
All of those mean the same thing.
所有这些意思都是一样的
So all of this is to say, equal equals, all it does is it uses the golden rule of equals to check the bits.
这一切的意思就是 等于等于 它只是使用等于的黄金法则来检查位
And in particular, for reference types, it checks, are these two memory boxes pointing at the exact same object?
特别是对于引用类型 它检查的是 这两个内存盒子是否指向完全相同的对象
Do they have the same address?
它们有相同的地址吗
That's all that equal equals checks.
这就是等号检查的全部
But Maybe I want something different.
但是 也许我想要一些不同的东西
Maybe I want a semantic kind of equals.
也许我想要一种语义上的相等
So what does that mean?
那是什么意思呢
Maybe these two are really different objects.
也许这两个真的是不同的对象
They live in different places.
它们存在于不同的地方
But if I look at them, I feel like somehow they mean the same thing.
但是如果我看着它们 我觉得它们以某种方式表达着相同的意思
So if you think of objects as representing real-world things, I think that these two sets, even though they are two different sets living in different places in memory,
如果你把对象看作是代表现实世界的东西 我认为这两个集合 即使它们存在于内存中的不同位置
I think they really deeply represent the same thing.
我认为它们确实深刻地代表着同一件事情
So somehow, I want the equals method to return true on these two things.
在某种程度上 我希望equals方法在这两个对象上返回true
Because I feel like, you know what?
因为我觉得 你知道吗
Yeah, they're two different objects right now.
是的 它们现在是两个不同的对象
But I feel like they represent the same thing on some really deep philosophical level.
但我觉得它们在某种非常深刻的哲学层面上代表着相同的东西
So I could use the equals method.
我可以使用equals方法
And hopefully, I get true to tell me that these two, even though they're not the same object, they somehow represent the same kind of set.
希望我得到true告诉我 尽管它们不是同一个对象 它们以某种方式代表相同类型的集合
So I could try that.
我可以尝试一下
So I can go back here.
我可以回到这里
I will comment out toString.
我会注释掉toString
I'm done with you.
我已经完成了
And I'm going to come over here, and I'll do the same thing as before.
我要过来这里 然后我会做和之前一样的事情
So I have an ArraySet.
我有一个 ArraySet
I throw in 5, 23, 42.
我扔进去 5、23、42
I have another ArraySet.
我有另一个 ArraySet
I throw in 5, 23, 42.
我扔进去 5、23、42
Now, I called the word new twice.
现在 我两次调用了单词 new
One's right there.
一个就在那里
那个就在那儿
So there are two ArraySets living in memory.
内存中有两个 ArraySets 生活着
They both have the same items.
它们都有相同的项目
And so if I call s, I'll do this first.
如果我调用 s 我会先执行这个动作
If I call s equal equals s2, it will say false.
如果我调用 s 等于等于 s2 它会返回 false
They are pointing at different locations in memory.
它们指向内存中的不同位置
The arrows are pointing at different places.
箭头指向不同的地方
But what if I instead use equals?
但如果我改用等号呢?
And I said, don't tell me if they're the same reference.
而我说了,别告诉我它们是否是相同的引用
Tell me if they mean the same thing.
告诉我它们是否意思相同
Do they mean the same array set?
它们意思相同吗?
So I can run this, and hopefully I get true.
我可以运行这个 希望能得到 true
But in fact, I get false.
但实际上 我得到了 false
And the reason is because it's just like the two-string mistake we made, which is I look, and I look.
原因是因为它就像我们犯的两个字符串错误一样 我看 然后我看
There's no equals method.
没有 equals 方法
I never wrote an equals method.
我从来没有写过一个 equals 方法
So in fact, I am inheriting the equals method from the parent class.
事实上 我是从父类继承了 equals 方法
So if I go to the parent class, I can even click on this to see.
如果我去到父类 我甚至可以点击这个来看
If I go to the parent class and I look at what the parent class's equals method does, it just does equal equals.
如果我去到父类 看看父类的 equals 方法做了什么 它只是执行等号比较
OK, kind of anticlimactic.
好吧 有点没什么意思
Here, I'll click on it just to show you.
在这里 我会点击它只是为了给你看
There it is.
这就是它
The object method, like this is actually object.java, the equals method.
对象方法就像这样实际上是object.java中的equals方法
What does it do?
它是做什么的
It just returns this equal equals object.
它只是返回这个等于等于对象
So if you don't write an equals method, you inherit the default equals method from the object class, which just does equal equals, checks if they're the same bits.
如果你不写一个equals方法 你就会继承object类的默认equals方法 它只是进行等于等于的检查 检查它们是否是相同的位
But I don't want that.
但我不想要那个
I want my own custom, nice-looking code that tells me if these two sets represent the same thing, even if they are different objects in memory.
我想要我的自定义、漂亮的代码 告诉我这两个集合是否代表相同的东西 即使它们在内存中是不同的对象
So that's my next goal.
这是我的下一个目标
I'm going to try to write something to check if these are the same thing in memory, or if they represent the same thing, even if they are not in the same location in memory.
我要尝试写点东西来检查这些是否在内存中相同 或者它们表示的是同一件事 即使它们不在内存中的同一位置
OK, so before I do that, I'm going to go on a three-minute detour, if that's OK with everyone.
在我这样做之前 我要走一个三分钟的小弯路 如果大家都没意见的话
Because someone asked it to, and people ask it every semester.
因为有人要求这样做 每个学期人们都会问这个问题
So people always ask, what the heck is this?
人们总是问 这到底是什么鬼东西
This is from lecture two.
这是来自第二讲
Remember, we did static methods.
记住 我们做了静态方法
If I am bigger than the other dog, return this.
如果我比另一只狗大 就返回这个
What is this?
这是什么
Well, this is a special keyword, and it tells you a reference to the current object.
这是一个特殊的关键字 它告诉你一个指向当前对象的引用
So just like you remember the new keyword, the new keyword would shout to the worlds, this is the address of my brand new walrus, or my brand new car, or my brand new dog.
就像你记得新关键字一样 新关键字会向世界大喊 这是我的全新海象的地址 或者我的全新汽车 或者我的全新狗
Well, this keyword, it shouts not the address of the new created object, but the address of the current object.
这个关键字 它喊的不是新创建对象的地址 而是当前对象的地址
So if I say, return this, I'm saying, return whichever dog is currently executing the maxDog method.
如果我说 返回这个 我是在说 返回当前正在执行 maxDog 方法的那只狗
That's what the keyword this says.
这就是关键字 this 的含义
It shouts and screams a reference or the address of the current object.
它喊喊叫叫地引用或指出当前对象的地址
OK.
This is another thing that people love to ask, which is, well, what's the difference between writing this.size and size?
这是另一件人们喜欢问的事情 那就是 写this.size和size之间有什么区别
And it turns out that in Java, both of these are the same.
结果在Java中 这两者是相同的
So if you do not specify this.size, Java will look in the code and say, well, there's only one thing currently called size.
如果你不指定this.size Java会在代码中查找并说 当前只有一件东西叫做size
It's the instance variable called Size.
它是叫做的实例变量 Size
So whether you say this.size to explicitly say, I want the current object's instance variable size, or if you just say size, Java will treat it the same.
无论你明确地说this.size 表示我要当前对象的实例变量size 还是只说size Java都会以相同的方式对待它
If it sees size, it knows, well, there's only one thing called size.
如果它看到size 它知道 只有一件叫做size的东西
It's the instance variable in the current object.
这是当前对象的实例变量
So if you write size, you write this.size, same thing.
如果你写size 你写this.size 一样的
One warning, though, is that if you start to call multiple things size, try to get clever,
不过 要注意的是 如果你开始给多个东西起名字叫size 尝试变聪明
and you say there's an instance variable called size, and there's also a local variable, this argument, called size,
你说有一个叫做size的实例变量 还有一个叫做size的局部变量 这个参数
well, now you have a problem.
那么 现在你有一个问题
You have two things called size.
你有两个叫做size的东西
So if you say size, Java gets confused.
如果你说size  Java 会搞混
It says, there's two things called size.
它说 有两个叫 size 的东西
Which one do you want?
你要哪个
And here, it ends up defaulting to the argument.
而在这里 它最终默认为参数
So if you say size equals size, it is not smart enough to realize that you're talking about two different variables, both called size.
如果你说 size 等于 size 它并不聪明到足以意识到你在谈论两个不同的变量 都叫做 size
Sometimes people call this hiding.
有时人们称之为隐藏
This one is hiding the other size variable.
这个正在隐藏另一个 size 变量
So if you write size equals size, it does nothing.
如果你写size等于size 它什么也不做
So in this case, you really have to be more specific and tell Java, there are two things called size.
在这种情况下 你真的必须更加具体地告诉Java 有两个叫做size的东西
On the left-hand side, I want the instance variable size, this current object's instance variable size.
在左边 我想要实例变量size 这个当前对象的实例变量size
And on the right-hand side, I want the argument called size.
而在右边 我想要叫做size的参数
If this is making your brain melt, my recommendation is to not name a bunch of variables the same thing.
如果这让你感到头脑混乱 我的建议是不要给一堆变量取相同的名字
So don't go around writing Project 1C with, like, 20 variables all called size.
不要写Project 1C 然后用20个名为size的变量
Instead, if you call it something like s, then whether or not you write this,
相反 如果你把它称为s 那么无论你是否写这个,
You're OK.
没问题
So it's less vulnerable to mistakes, I would say, if you use different variables.
这样的话 如果你使用不同的变量 我会说它更不容易出错
But if you really want to, you can do the thing on the right.
但如果你真的想的话 你可以在右边做这件事
In this case, you would just have to specify which size do you mean, because you have two things called size.
在这种情况下 你只需要指定你指的是哪个尺寸 因为你有两个叫做 size 的东西
OK.
So back to our topic.
那么回到我们的话题
That was our digression.
这就是我们的离题
Are we OK with it?
我们对此满意吗
This current object, sometimes usable, sometimes not.
这个当前对象 有时可用 有时不可用
OK.
Or sometimes you have to use it, sometimes you don't.
或者有时候你必须使用它 有时候你不必
OK.
So back to our task, which was that the object method, its equals method, just does double equals.
回到我们的任务 就是对象方法 它的equals方法 只是做双等号比较
In other words, it just checks if the two things that I'm comparing point at the same object.
换句话说 它只是检查我正在比较的两个东西是否指向同一个对象
But I don't want that.
但我不想要那个
I want a more interesting type of equals.
我想要一种更有趣的等于类型
I want to say, do they mean the same thing, even if they're not the same object?
我想说 它们是否意味着相同的事情 即使它们不是同一个对象
So I'm going to go and write this.
我要去写这个
Right now, it's using equal equals.
现在它正在使用等于等于
It's using the inherited version from the object class, which returns false.
它正在使用从对象类继承的版本 它返回false
It says these two are not equal because they are two different array sets in memory.
它说这两个不相等 因为它们是内存中的两个不同的数组集
I don't like that.
我不喜欢那样
I want them to be- I want this to return true because I feel like these represent the same thing.
我希望它们能够——我希望这个返回 true 因为我觉得它们代表了相同的事情
If I think of these sets like existing in the real world, they're somehow the same set.
如果我把这些集合想象成存在于现实世界中 它们在某种程度上是相同的集合
So how do I do that?
那我该怎么做呢
Well, I can go in and I can override what the boss says.
好吧 我可以进去 我可以覆盖老板说的话
So I can say, you know what?
我可以说 你知道吗
I don't like the equals method that you wrote.
我不喜欢你写的 equals 方法
I'm going to write my own.
我要写我的自己的
So I'm going to write my own equals method.
我要写我的自己的 equals 方法
And I could do something like this.
我可以做类似这样的事情
Am I equal to another ArraySet?
我是否等于另一个 ArraySet
And just to double-check, I'll put in the override tag.
只是为了再次确认 我会添加 override 标签
And in this case, the override tag complains.
在这种情况下 override 标签会抱怨
And it actually says, you're not overriding.
实际上它会说 你没有重写
There is no method in the object class that says equals ArraySet.
对象类中没有一个叫做 equals 的方法
And if you've done this and you see this, that's because you've made the rookie mistake of saying ArraySet here.
如果你做了这个并且看到了这个 那是因为你犯了初学者的错误 这里应该是对象集
It's supposed to be object, because the object method, it's equals method.
应该是对象 因为对象方法 它的 equals 方法
Where is it?
它在哪里
Right there?
就在那儿
No?
不是吗
Right there?
就在那儿
See, it says public Boolean equals object.
看 它说public boolean equals (object obj)
And if you want to overwrite it, then you have to put object here.
如果你想要覆盖它 那么你必须在这里放置object
It's got to be exactly the same.
它必须完全相同
So the overwrite attack can catch you if you do something silly like this.
覆盖攻击会在你做一些愚蠢的事情时抓住你
It will tell you, no, you're not overwriting.
它会告诉你 不 你没有覆盖
You have to put object there.
你必须在那里放置object
Great, so how do I check if two ArraySets mean the same thing?
太好了 那我怎么检查两个ArraySets是否表示相同的东西呢
Well, in this case, I have to be a little bit careful, because what if the object that comes in is not an ArraySet?
好吧 在这种情况下 我得小心一点 因为如果进来的对象不是一个数组集合呢
What if someone asks if the ArraySet is equal to a list?
如果有人问数组集合是否等于列表呢
Or what if someone asks, is the ArraySet equal to dog?
或者如果有人问 数组集合是否等于狗呢
Well, now I have to be careful.
好了 现在我得小心了
So the way to do it is I'm going to use a new keyword.
做法就是我要使用一个新的关键字
This is the last new keyword you have to learn in Java.
这是你在Java中需要学习的最后一个新关键字
It is also the strangest, so bear with me.
它也是最奇怪的 所以请跟着我
So I'm going to write syntax that's going to melt your brain for just one second.
我要写的语法会在短短一秒钟内让你的大脑短路
I'm going to write if O, the object that I pass in, is an instance of the ArraySet class.
我要写的是一个条件语句 检查我传入的对象 o 是否是 ArraySet 类的实例
So this is asking the question, object, are you a type ArraySet?
这就是在问这个对象 你是不是 ArraySet 类型的
Or are you a type something else, dog or whatever?
还是其他类型的 比如狗啥的
OK, and then?
然后呢
It's going to return true or false.
它会返回 true 或 false
So if this returns false, O is not an instance of ArraySet.
如果返回 false 说明 o 不是 ArraySet 的实例
That is, it's something else.
那是 它是其他东西
It's a dog.
它是一只狗
It's a cat.
它是一只猫
And in that case, I'll return false.
在那种情况下 我会返回 false
I'll say, not O was not an ArraySet.
我要说 o 不是 ArraySet
OK, great.
太棒了
And here I can even say, checks if O is an ArraySet.
在这里 我甚至可以说 检查 o 是否为 ArraySet
That's the instance of keyword.
这就是关键字的实例
So you thought that was weird.
你觉得这很奇怪
It's about to get weirder.
事情马上会变得更奇怪
Because if O is an instance of ArraySet, this weird instance of keyword can actually take in one extra parameter, which I'm going to put here.
因为如果o 是ArraySet的一个实例 这个奇怪的关键字实例实际上可以多接受一个参数 我会放在这里
And so what does this even mean?
这到底是什么意思呢
This is starting to become weird and horrible.
这开始变得既奇怪又可怕
Basically, what this is saying is these first words, they say, is o an instance of ArraySet?
基本上 这意味着这些第一个词 它们是在问 o是ArraySet的一个实例吗
If it's not, then this returns false.
如果不是 那么返回false
If this is true, it does a bonus thing for you, which is it will create a new variable called otherArraySet of type ArraySet.
如果为true 它将为你执行一个额外的操作 即它将创建一个名为otherArraySet的新变量 类型为ArraySet
So in other words, this otherArraySet variable, it's the same thing as o. They contain the same reference.
换句话说 这个otherArraySet变量 它和o是一样的 它们包含相同的引用
But it has been cast to an ArraySet for you.
但它已经被转换为一个ArraySet供你使用
OK, here it is in slide format, since it's probably been melting your brain.
在这里以幻灯片格式呈现 因为它可能让你的大脑融化
So the way you read this is, if O is an instance of the dog class, this returns true or false.
阅读这个的方式是 如果 o是dog类的实例 那么返回true或false
And then, if this returns false, it's over.
然后 如果这返回false 就结束了
It returns false.
它返回 false
Nothing else happens.
什么都不会发生
However, if this thing returns true, you get a side effect.
然而 如果这个东西返回 true 你会得到一个副作用
You get like a little bonus gift, which is you get a new variable of type otadog.
你会得到一个小礼物 你会得到一个新的 uddaDog 类型的变量
And that type otadog has static type dog.
而这个 uddaDog 类型有静态类型 dog
So it's like implicitly doing a little cast for you.
它就像隐式地为你执行了一个小的类型转换
Because it knows if you're trying to check if O is an instance of dog, you probably, if it's true, you probably also want a variable that is O casted to a dog.
因为它知道如果你试图检查 o 是否是 dog 的一个实例 如果是 true 你可能也想要一个被转换为 dog 的变量
So it just does it for you.
它只是为你做了这件事
Sorry, I know it was confusing.
抱歉 我知道这很令人困惑
But again, the way to read it is if O is an instance of the ArraySet, if it's true, give me a new variable called otherArraySet, which I can now use.
但再次 阅读它的方式是 如果 o 是 ArraySet 的一个实例 如果是真的 给我一个新的变量叫 otherArraySet 我现在可以使用它了
And it's going to be of type ArraySet.
而且它的类型将是 ArraySet
OK.
So that was probably the weirdest part.
那可能是最奇怪的部分
The rest of this is hopefully smooth sailing.
希望剩下的部分顺利进行
So how do I check if two arrays mean the same thing?
那么我如何检查两个数组是否表示相同的东西呢
Well, first, I can check if their sizes are equal.
首先 我可以检查它们的大小是否相等
So I could say, if my size
我可以说 如果我的大小
is not equal to the other array set size, that is, we are not the same size, then I should return false.
不等于另一个数组集大小 也就是说 我们大小不同 那么我应该返回false
We cannot be the same thing if we have different sizes.
如果我们大小不同 我们就不能是相同的东西
So checks if we are the same size.
检查我们是否大小相同
And if not, I'll return false.
如果不是 我就返回false
Next thing I should check is, if we're the same size, are all of my items in the other array set?
接下来我要检查的是 如果我们大小相同 那么另一个数组中的所有项目是否都设置好了
So do we share the same items?
那么我们是否共享相同的项目
Well, how do I do that?
好吧 我该怎么做呢
I could iterate through my current object.
我可以遍历我的当前对象
So again, for I am this, iterating through current object, me.
再次强调 因为我是这样的 遍历当前对象 我
So I'll check, are all of my items in the other array set?
我会检查 另一个数组集中是否都有我的所有项目
OK.
And I can check, so I could say, if OtherArraySet does not contain the object that I'm looking at, then I should return false.
而且我可以检查 所以我可以说 如果 otherArraySet 不包含我正在查找的对象 那么我应该返回 false
Because I found something that I have that my buddy doesn't have.
因为我找到了一些我有而我的伙伴没有的东西
So we're not the same.
我们不一样
If I have 5 and my buddy doesn't have 5, we are not the same.
如果我有5而我的伙伴没有5 我们就不一样
However, if everything that I have, I have a 5, you have a 5, I have a 23, you have a 23, I have a 42, you have a 42.
然而 如果我所有的东西 我有一个5 你也有一个5 我有一个23 你也有一个23 我有一个42 你也有一个42
If this holds true the whole time, then I can finally return true and say, yes, we're the same.
如果这一直成立 那么我最终可以返回true并说 是的 我们是一样的
Because we're both array sets, we're both the same size, and everything that I have, you have too.
因为我们都是数组集合 大小都一样 我所有的东西 你也有
So after all this hard work, I can finally run this.
经过所有这些辛苦的努力 我终于可以运行这个
And again, the weirdest part was probably the instance of keyword, and I get true.
而且 可能最奇怪的部分是关键字的实例 我得到了真值
Two array sets are the same.
两个数组集合是相同的
They mean the same thing.
它们表示相同的意思
OK, so again, the weirdest thing.
再说一次 最奇怪的事情
Yeah, let's talk about the battery for the next speaker.
是的 让我们谈谈下一个演讲者的电池
We'll be good soon.
我们很快就会好的
OK.